Guide to the Walter and Martha Leuba Papers, 1735-1988 SC.1988.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Walter and Martha Leuba Papers
1735-1988
1902-1988
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Leuba, Martha
Leuba, Walter
SC.1988.01
30 Linear Feet (63 boxes, 1 oversize box)
Walter and Martha Leuba collected books, woodblock prints, and signed letters of writers, artists, and other notable figures. Walter Leuba was a prolific writer of poetry and prose, with a focus on literature and music. The papers in this collection document the Leubas' collecting activities, Walter's writing projects, and the Leubas' lives.
Previous Citation
Walter and Martha Leuba Papers, 1735-1988, SC.1988.01, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Related Material
Walter and Martha Leuba Book and Print Collection. See Special Collections for inventory of prints. All monographs are cataloged in PittCat, the library's online catalog.
Biography
Walter Leuba (1902-1983) and Martha Leuba (nee Dryburgh) (1909-1988) collected books, wood block prints, other art, and signed letters by writers, artists, and other notable figures. They were married in 1938 and lived for much of their lives at 516 Jacksonia Street on Pittsburgh's North Side. Walter's collecting activities began in the 1920's, around the time that he met his first wife, Mildred Wallach (1908-1932).
Walter Leuba spent his early life in New York, Rhode Island, and Pittsburgh. After high school, Leuba attended Carnegie Institute of Technology (now Carnegie Mellon University), where he studied fine art, English, and history. Through Porter Garnett, founder of the Laboratory Press at C.I.T., Leuba developed his love of finely printed and illustrated books.
Leuba left C.I.T. in 1923 for financial reasons and moved to New York. While there, he wrote poetry under the name Paul Sandoz and published his first book of verse,Legend, in 1925. After a year in Europe, Leuba returned to Pittsburgh in 1926. He married Mildred Wallach in 1927. Their son, Julian Christopher Leuba, nicknamed "Beppo," was born in 1929. In 1932, Leuba was laid off and the family lived on Mildred's wages until her death in December 1932, following a brief and sudden illness. In early 1933, Leuba left his son in the care of his paternal aunts in California. When Leuba brought his son back to Pittsburgh two years later, a succession of friends, relatives, and a children's home cared for Christopher until Leuba married Martha Dryburgh. In 1934, Leuba began working as a caseworker at the Allegheny County Board of Assistance. He earned a B.A. and an M.A. in social work from the University of Pittsburgh in 1947.
Leuba was a prolific writer of poetry and prose. He wrote frequent letters to the editors of the Times Literary Supplement and Pittsburgh newspapers, and contributed to literary journals and The Pittsburgh Point. In 1947, Macmillan published Leuba's Poems out of a Hat. In 1967 his George Saintsbury was published in the Twayne Men of Letters series. His books of poetry No Other Mirror and Quips and Cranks, the prose-poem Crusade, and Two Essays on Bach were privately printed. Leuba also produced a number of books through collaborative efforts. In 1947, his correspondence with Ernest Nevin Dilworth about modern education was published by Macmillan as Smith Unbound and received considerable critical notice. Leuba and Dilworth collaborated again on Two Dialogues: Norman Douglas and George Santayana in 1974. With Robert McCullough, Leuba wrote and took photos for The Pennsylvania Main Line Canal (1973). In addition, Leuba contributed poems to a collection of Norton Peterson woodcuts and text to a George Nama portfolio,Monument Studies.
Beginning in the 1970s, the Leubas began donating books and prints from their collection to the University Library System (ULS) of the University of Pittsburgh. After Martha Leuba's death in 1988, their remaining prints, books, and papers were transferred to the ULS Special Collections Department.
For a more detailed biography of Walter Leuba, please contact the ULS Special Collections Department at the University of Pittsburgh. Additional biographical material is collected in Series V, Personal Papers: Subseries 2, Biography and Genealogy.
Scope and Content Notes
The Walter and Martha Leuba Papers contain materials related to the Leubas' collecting and writing pursuits, including manuscripts, research notes, clippings, the Leuba's collection of autograph and typescript signed letters, catalogs and indexes of their collections, and wood blocks. They reflect the Leubas' interests in books, art, literature, and music. In addition, the collection contains materials related to the Leubas' lives, family, friends, and other interests; these include correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks, diaries, and personal papers.
The bulk of the material in the collection dates from within the Leubas' lifetimes, 1902 to 1988. Material from before 1902 is primarily from their collection of signed letters (Series III, ALS and TLS) and family records (Series V, Personal Papers). Some of the material, particularly in Series V, Personal Papers, pertains to Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, where the Leubas spent most of their adult lives; a small portion pertains to New York City, where Walter Leuba lived briefly.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into nine series:
Series I. Manuscripts
Series II. Correspondence
Series III. ALS and TLS
Series IV. Inventories and Notes
Series V. Personal Papers
Series VI. Photographs
Series VII. Scrapbooks
Series VIII. Ephemera
Series IX. Woodblocks
Private presses; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Manuscripts (Document genre); Scrapbooks; Wood blocks (Printing blocks); Ephemera; Photographs; Correspondence; Personal papers; Private press books; Fine books; Dilworth, Ernest; Leuba, Martha; Leuba, Walter
- Manuscripts, 1916-1981; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Series contains drafts, typscripts and manuscripts by Leuba and others. Some folders include materials found with manuscripts, such as notes, clippings, correspondence, and photographs. Series is divided into two subseries: Subseries 1, Manuscripts by Walter Leuba, and Subseries 2, Manuscripts by Other Authors. Materials are arranged alphabetically by title and author. Larger, legal size materials have been separated for storage purposes and are listed at the end of this Series.
  - Manuscripts by Walter Leuba, 1916-1981; 1.
    This subseries contains manuscripts of works written by or in collaboration with Walter Leuba, including Leuba's compilations and transcriptions of works by others. Leuba wrote broadly on his many interests; principal subjects are literature, British literary figures (e.g., George Saintsbury), and classical music (e.g., the works of J.S. Bach). He also wrote extensive poetry.
    The material in this series includes manuscripts and typescripts, as well as clippings of published letters and poetry. Folders are arranged alphabetically by manuscript title or, if untitled, by primary subject. Also included are folders of research and reading notes, clippings, correspondence, and other materials that relate to a specific manuscript or subject; these folders are filed with their associated manuscript or, if no manuscript exists, by their primary subject. Additional research and reading notes are in Series IV, Inventories and Notes; the notes in Series IV are not associated with a specific subject or known manuscript, or are related to multiple subjects or manuscripts.
    - Adjectives (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Andrew Valley, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Andrew Valley: A Chapter, May 2, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bach, J.S., and music - notes and manuscripts (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bach, J.S., and music - notes (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bach, J.S., and music - notes, clippings, and ephemera, 1942-1949 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
    - Beards and the Incidence of Beards (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Beware the Dictionary (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - A Bibliography of Unwritten Books (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - The Boy, July 11, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - British Authors Bibliography (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Canals of Pennsylvania: The Rise and Decline of an Inland Navigation System (WL with Robert McCullough), 1970 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
    - Centuries of Sentences (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
    - A Chronology of the Life and Work of Louise Imogen Guiney, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Includes documents on Alivisos Tassos and Porter Garnett
    - A Communication (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Compositions by Eli Siegel, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Compositions by Eli Siegel - notes and clippings, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Crusade, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Deadlock: An Alphabetical Handbook of Criticism, Definition, and Comment (A-M), 1941 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
    - Deadlock: An Alphabetical Handbook of Criticism, Definition, and Comment (N-Y), 1941 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Dickey, James (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Do You Want to Know Why Beethoven Was a Great Artist? (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Elections and money (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - English Lives: First Series, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Essays, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - An Examination Paper: "The Life & Opinions of Tristram Shandy, Gentleman" (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Far Worse Than Weeds, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Finding books in second-hand stores (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Five Savages (W.L. with Ernest Dilworth) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Fowler, H.W. - notes (W.L. with Ernest Dilworth), 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Fragments of Summer Conversations, circa 1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - The Frontier of Politics. Part I: The Reign of Andrew Jackson [Book Review] (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - George Saintsbury (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - George Saintsbury (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - George Saintsbury - Twayne Publishers documents, 1965-1973 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - George Saintsbury - notes and clippings, 1933-1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - George Saintsbury - notes, clippings, correspondence, draft m.s. (W.L. with Ernest Dilworth), 1933-1963 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - George Saintsbury Bibliography (incomplete), 1945 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - George Saintsbury Bibliography notes (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - A Handbook or Vademecum for Public Welfare Workers, circa 1963 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - How to Write a Poem - 1950-1970 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Imbrications (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Index to Imbrications (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Incidentals (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - The Indigent and Human Rights [Master's Thesis], 1946 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - John Keats: Ode to a Nightingale, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - John Keats: Ode to a Nightingale, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - John Keats: Ode to a Nightingale - notes and clippings, 1938-1964 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Laconics: Sentences, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - A Letter from Charles Lamb to Bernard Barton [Transcription] (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Letter to a Hornblower, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Letters to the press and reviews, 1929-1968 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Letters to the press, 1961-1966 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Libel (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - The Linden Tree, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - A Listener's Reflections on the Music of Bach and Others, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Previous title: A Bach Notebook: The Listener and Critical Opinion
    - A Bach Notebook: The Listener and Critical Opinion, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - A Bach Note-book and various notes (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Louis J. Lehrman: 12/10/1909-4/26/1973 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Louise Imogen Guiney, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Man-made (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Millet, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts, 1947-1966 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Music, July 19, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Nature and art (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Norton Peterson: 1916-1975 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Notes on Bulgarians, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - The Onion Field, July 18, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - The Pennsylvania Main Line Canal (WL with Robert McCullough), 1962 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - The Pennsylvania Main Line Canal (WL with Robert McCullough) - related material, 1955-1970 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Poem (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Poems - clippings, 1933-1968 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Poems, 1927-1948 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Poems, 1923-1971 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Poems, 1933-1967 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Poems with corrections, 1931-1956 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Poems [Transcription] (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Poetry essay (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Poetry essays - school papers, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Quips and Cranks, Etc., 1923-1964 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Quotations compilation (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
    - Quotations - note cards (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Reading Marlowe: Tamburlaine (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Reading Marlowe - draft, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Marlowe, C. - essays (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Revolution (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Rice-field Plus Struggle Equals Male, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Rice-field Plus Struggle Equals Male: Some Notes on an Ancient Chinese Pamphlet, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Small Boy, August 5, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Smith, Logan Pearsall - draft MS, notes, and clippings (W.L. with Ernest Dilworth), 1931-1947 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Smith Unbound (W.L. and Ernest Dilworth) (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Smith Unbound (W.L. and Ernest Dilworth) (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Smith Unbound clippings and reviews, 1946-1949 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      Also contains clippings re: Poems out of a Hat
    - Smith Unbound reviews, 1946-1947 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Some Characters From the Twentieth Century [1 copy] (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Some Characters From the Twentieth Century [2 copies] (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Sonnets anthology [Transcriptions] (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
    - Three Lives of Swift, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Swift, Jonathan - notes (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - To the All Excelling R.(ay) L.(ivingston) A.(rmstrong)…, December 30, 1941 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - To the Reader by Thomas Fuller [Transcription] (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Two Dialgoues: George Santayana, Norman Douglas (W.L. with Ernest Dilworth), 1974 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Douglas, Norman - notes, clippings, draft M.S. (W.L. with Ernest Dilworth), 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Vegetable Love and Other Observations (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Waiting for Godot essay (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Who will bury whom? (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - The Woodcuts of Alivisos Tassos (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Two Essays on Bach, 1972 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Bach, J.S., and music - essays, circa 1963 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Manuscripts by Other Authors, 1925-1984; 2.
    This subseries contains manuscripts and typescripts of works by writers other than Walter Leuba. Authors include family members (Christopher, Martha, and Mildred Leuba), colleagues and friends (e.g., Robert McCullough), and other individuals. Individual manuscripts are filed separately, with folders arranged alphabetically by name of author and then by title of manuscript, or by primary subject if untitled. Some folders also contain correspondence, notes, photographs, and other materials found with the manuscript. Larger materials have been separated for storage purposes and are listed at the end of this subseries.
    - Allegheny County Board of Assistance - For the Duration: October 1942 - October 1943 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Allegheny County Board of Assistance - For the Duration: October 1943 - October 1944, Vol. 2 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Anonymous – Mexico (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Bynner, Witter - The Jade Mountain, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Emerson, Edward - Gypo and Katie (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Emerson, Edward - The Prosecution Rests (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Emerson, Edward and Charles Williams - Love in Upper Sandusky (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Greenhood, David - The Ark and The Cross and Miscellaneous, 1926-1984 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Hayden, Rupert - Poems (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Huxley, Aldous - Essays on writers (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Typescript with edits on Gilbert White, Ruskin, Wilde, Lessing.
    - Leuba, Christopher - A Trip to Japan, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Leuba, Christopher - Visit to Nuristan, Summer 1970 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Leuba, Martha – The Brontës (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Leuba, Mildred – Book reviews (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - McCullough, Robert - A Skeptical Look at Official Crime Reports (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - McCullough, Robert - Traveling by Freighter, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Peterson, E.L. - Poems, 1925 - 1935 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      Also includes correspondence from Caroline Norton and writings by Stanley Burnshaw, James Daly, Donald Kirkley, William Geoffrey, Edwin Lewis
    - Storm, Hans Otto - Made in U.S.A. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Various Authors – Literary essays, 1963-1971 (Box 63, Folder 3)
      Essays by Stanley Burnshaw, Samuel L. Macey
- Correspondence, II.
  Series contains correspondence between Leuba and a range of personal and professional contacts. Series has been arranged into 4 subseries: (1) Personal Correspondence, (2) Professional Correspondence, (3) Correspondence with Mildred and (4)Correspondence from Walter Leuba. An address book listing Leuba contacts is found at the beginning of Subseries 1 (Personal Correspondence). Except where noted, correspondence is grouped alphabetically by last name or corporate name. The bulk of the letters are addressed to either Walter Leuba; some letters are addressed to Paul Sandoz (Walter Leuba's pen-name), Mildred Leuba, Martha Leuba, and Christopher Leuba (aka Beppo). Correspondents are listed with their spouses when appropriate.
  - Personal Correspondence, 1.
    Subseries contains correspondence between Leuba and colleagues, friends, and family. An address book listing Leuba contacts is fund at the beginning of this subseries. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by last name, where available.
    - Address Books (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - [Unknown], 1961-1962 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - _____, Bess, circa 1948 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - _____, Bob & Beverly, 1963-1968 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - _____, Bud, Mary, & Suzy (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - _____, Frank, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - _____, Henry, 1928-1940 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - _____, Kay & Milton, 1942-1954 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - _____, Rosalia & Abe, 1932- 1976 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Armstrong, Ray, 1947- 1976 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Aston, Charles Jr. - University of Pittsburgh, 1971- 1982 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Austern, Norman - University of Pittsburgh, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Bennett, Alice, 1926-1930 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Bergmann, Robert, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Bopes, Charles, 1926-1940 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Bridge, Lionel – Sheed and Ward Publishers, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - [Brindle], John ("Jack") & Kaye, 1965- 1976 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Bundy, Esther Vale, 1945- 1986 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Burnshaw, Stanley, 1925-1978 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Bynner, Witter, 1924-1961 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Caldwell, Dr. J.D., 1926 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Clapp, Frederick Mortimer, 1947-1966 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Cohen, Hermann – Chiswick Bookshop, 1963-1971 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Conroy, Jack, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Crozier, Sid, 1924 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Dawson, Major Ernest & Edith, 1928-1937 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Deval, Laurie – Elkin Mathews Ltd., 1950-1953 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Dilworth, Ernest - postcards, 1937-1967 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Fisher, Francis C. – Brenlove and Fisher, Attorneys at Law (re: Estate of William Dryburgh), 1967-1969 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Frazier, John, 1973-1977 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Frederick, Halsey & Celina, 1961-1963 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Garnett, Porter (transcriptions), 1947-1950 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Geoffrey, William ("Billy") & Elizabeth, 1933-1937 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Geoffrey, William ("Billy") & Elizabeth, 1938-1974 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Gildersleeve, Karl & Nancy, 1962-1985 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Gladis, Pat – University of Pittsburgh, 1971-1977 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Godine, David, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Goodfellow, Dorothy, 1972-1975 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Gormly, John, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Greenhood, Clarence David ("Clink") & Billy, 1982-1984 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Gunther, Anne, 1924-1948 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Gunther, Helene, 1927-1942 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Heid, Lee Paul, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Hoagland, Clayton, 1968-1981 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Hogan, James Denton ("Dinty") (transcriptions), 1923-1929 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Hogan, James Denton ("Dinty"), 1924-1956 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Jaffe, Arthur, 1968-1974 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Kalberer, Edward, Mary & Marus, 1941-1978 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Kallet, Tony, 1977-1978 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Kirkley, Donald, 1926-1931 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Kiter, Bess & Clare, 1954-1963 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Knobelsdorff, Constance, 1934 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Kottler, Barnett, 1962-1964 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Kraft, James – The Witter Bynner Foundation, 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Lehrmann, Louis & Sara, 1957-1963 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Leuba, Armand & Beula, 1927-1958 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Leuba, Cecile ("Tante Cecile"), 1924-1945 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Leuba, Cecile & Jeanne ("Tante Cecile & Tante Jeanne"), 1932-1950 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Leuba, Christopher, 1936-1951 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Leuba, Christopher, 1952-1956 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Leuba, Christopher, 1970-1978 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Leuba, Christopher, 1972-1976 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Leuba, Christopher, 1978-1980 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Leuba, Christopher, 1980-1987 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Leuba, Christopher, 1987-1988 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Christopher Leuba Letters II, 1938-1963 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
    - Christopher Leuba Letters III, 1964-1970 (Box 21, Folder 3-4)
    - Christopher Leuba Letters IV part 1 of 2, 1971-1974 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Christopher Leuba Letters IV part 2 of 2, 1971-1974 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Leuba, Dick & Mary, 1961-1975 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Leuba, Harald Richard & Lois (nee Reed), & Nancy (nee Kingsbury), 1961-1976 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Leuba, Harald Sandoz Carstensen & Irene, & Charmian (nee Lee), & Dorothy, 1921-1977 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Leuba, Henri & Cecile ("Oma & Opa"), 1910-1918 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Leuba, Lily, 1963-1972 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Leuba, Jeanne ("Tante Jeanne"), 1950-1961 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Leuba, Jeanne (nee Gunther) ("Mother Jeanne"), 1925-1928 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Leuba, Karl, 1961-1962 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Leuba, Martha (nee Volquarts) ("Mother"), 1916-1928 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Leuba, Samuel ("Dad"), 1921-1954 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Leuba, Samuel & Loula (nee Carroll) ("Dad & Mother Lou"), 1938-1949 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Liggett, Thomas – World Peace News, 1974-1977 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Loewinger, Bob, 1959-1974 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Long, Anton, 1971-1979 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Long, Haniel, 1923-1956 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Louis, Frida, circa 1947 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Loveman, Samuel, 1929-1940 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - McCullough, Robert, 1960-1966 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - McCullough, Robert, 1967-1972 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - McCullough, Robert, 1973-1986 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - McCullough, Robert – Letters from Mexico, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - McCullough, Robert – Travel Letters, 1965 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - McCullough, Robert – Travel Letters, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Mockel, Henry & Beverly – Pioneer Art Gallery, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Nesbitt, Alexander and Buchert, Ilse, 1967-1969 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Patterson, Thomas W., 1959 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Pendleton, Marguerite L., 1949-1950 (Box 24, Folder 6)